## **Subhankar Rout**

**User Experience Designer | Product Designer** 

- +91 9337663465
- subhankarrout.kiit@gmail.com
- linkedin.com/in/subhankarrout
- www.subhankarrout.in
- behance.net/routsubhankar

## **Profile Summary**

As a UI/UX Designer, I merge creativity with technical expertise to craft engaging designs, leading numerous projects that boost user satisfaction by an average of 30%. My collaborative efforts with 100+ professionals yield innovative designs that resonate deeply with users, reflecting a commitment to excellence in user experience.

## **Experience**

#### Senior User Experience Designer

Deligence Technologies Inc. | Jan 2024 - Present

- As a Senior UI/UX Designer, my tasks include designing wireframes, prototypes, user research and user flows to enhance the overall user experience.
- I revamped a leading educational game's UI/UX, increasing user engagement by 20%, and reduced user drop-off rates by 15%.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to integrate user feedback into design iterations, resulting in a user satisfaction score increase of 30%.

#### **Visual Interaction Designer**

RPATech, Gurugram | Oct 2020 - January 2024

- As a Visual Interaction Designer, I crafted user interfaces and experiences for our Robotic Process Automation (RPA) projects.
- Enhanced learning experiences through collaborative stakeholder engagement and effective design solutions.
- Developed engaging visual content for top-rated online courses, resulting in a 40% increase in course enrollment on platforms like Coursera and Udemy.

## **Certifications**

#### **UX Design Professional Certification**

Google LLC | 2023

Learned to conduct research, white boarding, and prototype creation in UX Design.

#### **User Experience Designer Certification Course**

LinkedIn Learning | 2021

• Gained skills in using UI/UX tools for designing and prototyping user interfaces.

# Brand Management: Aligning Business, Brand and Behavior London Business School | 2021

Learned to align brand strategy with product development.

## How to ChatGPT: Master the Art of Prompt Engineering

Udemy Learning | 2023

• Learned prompt engineering and how to effectively use ChatGPT.

#### The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing

Google Learning | 2020

Learned how websites work, SEO, and digital business growth.

## **Education**

#### GIET University, Gunupur

Bachelor of Technology | 2017 - 2021

### **Skills**

#### Design

 $\mbox{ User Experience} \cdot \mbox{Interaction Design} \cdot \mbox{ User Interface} \cdot \mbox{Prototyping} \cdot \mbox{ Visual Design} \cdot \mbox{Wireframing} \cdot \mbox{Mockups Design}$ 

#### Research

 $\label{lem:user_Interviews} \ \ \text{User Testing} \cdot \ \text{Information Architecture} \cdot \ \text{Journey} \\ \ \ \text{Mapping} \cdot \ \ \text{Quantitative Analysis} \cdot \ \ \text{A/B Testing} \cdot \ \ \text{Competitor Analysis} \cdot \ \ \\ \ \ \text{Brand Strategy}$ 

#### Software

Figma · Miro · Photoshop · Premiere Pro · AfterEffects · Adobe XD · Camtasia · Jira · Notion · Illustrator · HTML · CSS · Js (basic)

#### Visual Design

Poster Design  $\cdot$  Branding  $\cdot$  Typography  $\cdot$  Iconography  $\cdot$  Book Design  $\cdot$  App Design  $\cdot$  Web Design, Stylesheets and Guidelines

#### Other Skills

Collaboration and Communication  $\cdot$  Team Management  $\cdot$  Project Management

#### **Achievements**

UI Design Excellence - Deligence Technologies Inc. | 2024
Annual Excellence Award by CEO - RPATech | 2022
Creativity and Innovation Recognition by AVP - RPATech | 2021
Innovation Challenge Runners-up - IEEE GIETU | 2020
Filmmaker Champion – NSS MBD Camp | 2019
Best Filmmaker Award - GIET University | 2018

### **Extra-curricular Activities**

- Authored and published English novel, showcasing creativity and storytelling skills.
- Recognized by the Commissioner of Municipality, Rourkela, for contributions to literature and culture.
- Featured in news outlets for both novel and music albums.
- Creating a platform to inspire new designers "DesignUX"
- Created and led the "OdiCoder" YouTube channel, inspiring coding enthusiasts in the local language.
- Created and managed the "S4 Cinesphere" YouTube channel, producing music albums and short films during college.

## Language

#### English, Hindi, Odia

(Proficient in understanding, writing, and speaking)